SHRIRAM SUNDER

⊠ SS6G11@SOTON.AC.UK

Personal Statement

I am Mechanical Engineer, well versed in Scientific Computing practices and have extensive experience in control techniques & optimisation algorithms. I also have over 18 months of experience in systems and chassis designs, designing BMS's for a hybrid motorcycle and precision manufacturing skills.

SKILLS

Tools MATLAB, Mathematica

Com Protocols CAN, RS232

Textual Languages C, Embedded C, C#, C++ & Python Graphical Languages Simulink, LabVIEW, TestStand, VeriStand

Parallel Computing Directives OpenMP, MPI, CUDA-C

Scripts HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, bash, PowerShell

CAD SolidWorks

EDUCATION

Degree MEng - Mech. Engineering (Advanced Materials)

Period September 2011 — June 2015

AWARDS £1500 for exceptional academic performance

Rank (2:1) Upper Second Class with Honours

University University of Southampton Southampton, UK

EXPERIENCE

EMPLOYER University of Cambridge, Department of Chemistry

Period August 2015 — October 2015

Title System Design for Reaction Optimisation

DESC: Implementing algorithms in micro-flow fluid systems to optimise re-

action speed quality and and automate systems. Involved optimisation in 2D and 3D spaces, with both local and global heuristic

methods.

Skills NI Labview, Python, MatLab, Algorithm Design

EMPLOYER University of Southampton + Schlumberger

Period June 2015 — September 2015

Title Control Development of a Downhole Drill String Experi-

ment

DESC: Experimental testing with real oilfield components under simulated

downhole drilling conditions. Involves data interpretation, and making recommendations to the industrial sponsor based on their find-

ings.

Skills NI Labview, PID, Control theory

EMPLOYER University of Southampton, Department of Chemistry

Period July 2015 — September 2015 (Voluntary Internship)

TITLE Exploring dopant(Nb,Mo,Ta) properties induced in TCO's

 (SnO_2)

DESC: Introduced to Computational Material Science and Atomistic Sim-

ulations.Involved a significant amount of Bash Scripting and data

accumulation/interpretation.

SKILLS CRYSTAL, Fortran, C, Python (Pandas, Scrapy), GnuPlot

DISSERTATION

TITLE Hybrid Range Extending Motorcycle

Year Year 4

DESC. Involved the building of a series hybrid (IC-Electric) system on a

motorbike in order to provide a solution for a light medium range vehicle. Personal responsibilities included installing a BMS system for the first iteration of the bike, as well as design a GUI for the

bike's simulator.

Skills Motorbike Simulator (Simulink), Simulator GUI and BMS

system design

EXTRA-CURRICULAR COURSES AND PROJECTS

TITLE LabView Core 1

Duration June 2015 - July 2015

Training LabView, Advanced Control systems

RESULT Developed fluency in LabVIEW and Control Algorithms. Also de-

veloped skills that help manipulate serial interface devices.

PROJECT(S) Programming in Parallel MPI and MPP

Duration January 2015 - June 2015

Training C and C++ and Python (Pandas, GnuPlot)

RESULT Developed fundamental concepts of MPI and MPP interfaces, and

gained exposure towards batch programming, benchmarking and dif-

ferentiating

PROJECT GPS-Quadcopter Integration

DURATION June 2015- present

Training Improved previous concept, by including a gps tracking, relaying

data into a local server and plot the path using Google Maps API.

Result Work still in progress

PROJECT Southampton University Formula Student

Duration September 2012- September 2014

Training Small parts and precision parts manufacturing and exten-

sive use of Solid-Works software.

RESULT Resulted in the first car to qualify in Formula Student 2013 from the

university in 10 years, and gained significant experience in manufac-

turing small parts for the car.